Now let's talk about AWS WaveLengths.
So, WaveLength Zones are infrastructure deployments,
embedded within the telecommunications providers'
datacenters at the edge of 5G networks.
The idea is that whenever you see 5G in your questions,
this is most likely going to be WaveLength,
but let's go a little bit deeper in this.
So the idea is that you're able to deploy some AWS services
directly to the edge on the 5G networks.
For example, you can deploy easy two instances,
EBS volumes, even VPC to a WaveLength Zone.
So, say you have a, for example
a telecom carrier, has a 5G network
and you're going to have a WaveLength Zone
and through a carrier gateway, you're able to
actually deploy an easy two instance on that Zone.
But that zone belongs to the 5G network itself,
so that whenever a user on the 5G for a mobile device
accesses your WaveLength Zone,
they have really, really low latency
because the application is really deployed at the edge.
So, this is the whole idea behind WaveLength is to
give ultra-low latency to applications through 5G networks.
The traffic, for example, in this example,
never leaves the Communication Service Provider,
the CSP network.
It actually never reaches AWS, but in case you
do need to have a secure connection to AWS, we can.
So, the wavelength zone is connected to the parent region.
In case, for example, your easy two instances
in your WaveLength Zone needs to access a database.
For example, RDS or DynamoDB,
within your main parents, AWS Region.
There is no additional charges
or service agreements for using WaveLength.
And the use cases for this are multiple.
This is to have Smart Cities, ML-assisted diagnostics,
ConnectedVehicles, Interactive Live Video Streams,
AR and VR, Real-time Gaming.
Anything that requires really low latency
and to be very, very close at the edge to your users.
And this is a use case enabled by 5G.
So, I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.